Guide to the Brooklyn newsletter collection ARC.174
Brooklyn Historical Society
Brooklyn newsletter collection
1877-2010
1960-2000
Brooklyn Historical Society
East Midwood Jewish Center (New York, N.Y.)
Flatlands Historical Foundation (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
Los Angeles Dodgers (Baseball team). Alumni Association
Brooklyn Sports Foundation (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
Brooklyn Economic Development Corporation
Brooklyn In Touch Information Center (New York, N.Y.)
Brooklyn Center for the Urban Environment. Prospect Park Environmental Center (PPEC). Center for the Urban Environment
Prospect Park Environmental Center (New York, N.Y.)
Better Brooklyn Committee
Boro Park Historical Society
Brooklyn Library Council
Paragon Progressive Federal Credit Union
Paragon Progressive Community Association
Friends of Gateway (New York, N.Y.)
Neighborhood Open Space Coalition (New York, N.Y.)
Lubavitch Youth Organization (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
Green-Wood Historic Fund
Greensward Foundation
Gateway National Recreation Area (Agency: U.S.)
Securities Industry Automation Corporation
Gravesend Historical Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
Brooklyn Urban League (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
Brooklyn Union Gas Company
Gowanus Arts Exchange
Gay Friends & Neighbors, Ltd. Brooklyn
Fulton Mall Improvement Association
Flatlands Chamber of Commerce (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
Young Women's Christian Association (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
Ascent Institute (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
Machne Israel
Congregation Beth Elohim (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
New York (N.Y.). Parks and Recreation, Brooklyn
Community Board No. 9 (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.). Office of Brooklyn Borough President
Society for the Historical Preservation of the Fourteenth Brooklyn State Militia Infantry (New Jersey)
Home Title Insurance Company (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
Italian Historical Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
Citizens for a Better New York
Coney Island Hysterical Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
Central Brooklyn Model Cities
Positive Focus, Inc. (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
Scandinavian East Coast Museum (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
Namm's (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
Telephone Pioneers of America. Long Island Empire Chapter
Douglas MacArthur Republican Club (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.)
ARC.174
3.3 Linear Feet in four document boxes and one flat box
The Brooklyn newsletter collection, dated 1877 to 2010 (bulk 1960 to 2000) and measuring 3.3 linear feet, contains newsletters from Brooklyn-based businesses and organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
Original issues from Volumes 1 and 2 of Guy Pierrepont's Weekly Society Bulletin are in very fragile condition and should not be used unless the provided preservation photocopies will not suffice for the researcher's purpose.
Otherwise this collection is open to researchers without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Source and date of acquisition for many items in the collection are unknown. Where the items' source(s) are known, that information is indicated at the file level. Many were evidently sent to the Brooklyn Historical Society or Brooklyn Public Library directly.
Scope and Contents
The Brooklyn newsletter collection, dated 1877 to 2010 (bulk 1960 to 2000) and measuring 3.3 linear feet, contains newsletters from Brooklyn-based businesses and organizations. The newsletters vary in length and quality and touch on a variety of different subjects including Brooklyn neighborhoods, housing, economic issues, and community updates.
Related Materials
Brooklyn neighborhood associations and civic organizations publications (ARC.167)
Carlisle Indian: The Newsletter of the Carlisle Club (BCMS.0024)
Linewaiters' Gazette Collection (BCMS.0027)
Materials from the various organizations and businesses represented here can also be found in the Brooklyn ephemera collection (BCMS.0007) and the Brooklyn Historical Society ephemera collection (ARC.272).
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
If digital surrogates exist, they should be used in place of the originals whenever possible.
Guy Pierrepont's weekly society bulletin; Attitude (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.); Midwout magazine; Luhn's rugby bulletin; Jewish community guide, Brooklyn edition; Good news paper (Newsletter); Nuggets (Newsletter); Newsletters; Brooklyn Bridge bulletin; Brooklyn bums newsletter; Astella action news; Brooklyn berichten (Newsletter); Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Business enterprises |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Parks |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Theaters |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) |x Social life and customs
- 14th Brooklyn Society News, 1980-1982 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Vols. 1-3. Published quarterly by the Society for the Historical Preservation of the Fourteenth Brooklyn State Militia Infantry (84th New York Infantry) Incorporated.
  Related Materials
  See also The Red Legged Devil.
- The A & S Spotlight, 1968 Fall (Box 1)
  Vol. 30 No. 3. Published by Abraham & Straus.
- A Little News, 1983, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
  Published by Greensward Foundation, Inc., "the friends of Central Park, Prospect Park, Fort Greene Park, Branch Brook Park, Druid Hill Park and Cadwalader Park."
- The Arch, 2004 Fall (Box 1)
  Vol. V No. 2. Published by the Green-Wood Historic Fund of Green-Wood Cemetery.
- Ascent, 1989 Summer (Box 1)
  Number 15 (Vol. V No. 3). A quarterly publication of the Ascent Institute: Inner dimensions of Jewish life.
- Astella Action News, 1986, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 1986, Box 5, Folder 2005)
  Vol. 9 No. 1; Vol. 11 No. 4. Astella Development Corporation, Coney Island.
- The Attitude, 1989 December 1 (Box 1)
  Vol. 1 No. 1. Arts and culture magazine published by Malcolm Smart. Includes AIDS Watch column.
- The Avonian, 1877 December 7 (Box 1)
  Vol. I No. 3. Published by the Avonian Dramatic Association.
- Bang newsletter, 1998 Summer (Box 1)
  Published seasonally by the Brooklyn Alliance of Neighborhood Gardens (BANG).
- BEDC Update, 1985-1992 (Box 5)
  Vols. V-X. Published by the Brooklyn Economic Development Corporation.
- The Bedford Stuyvesant Little League News, 1963 (Box 1)
  Vol. IX Nos. 1 and 2. "Published as a Service to the Youth of the Community by the Breevort Savings Bank."
- The Bridge, 1995-1999 (Box 1)
  Dignity/Brooklyn, local chapter of Dignity/USA. "The newsletter of Brooklyn's caring community of lesbian and gay Roman Catholics and their friends." Includes some Dignity/USA newsletters also.
- Brooklyn Berichten, 1979 April-May, 1990 August (Box 1)
  Piet E. Schreuders, Managing Editor.
- Brooklyn Bridge Bulletin, 1979-1984 (Box 1)
  Published in Holland by Ed Schilders and Piet Schreuders.
- The Brooklyn Bugle, 1967 September (Box 1)
  Vol. 25 No. 4. Published monthly by the Brooklyn chapter of the National Association of Accountants (NAA).
- The Brooklyn Bums newsletter, 1987-1989 (Box 1)
  Nos. 1-25. Published by Metro Sports Look, Inc., NJ.
- Brooklyn in Touch Neighborhood News, 1980-1985 (Box 1)
  Vols. 1-5
- Brooklyn Junior League News, 1966 June (Box 1)
  Vol. XXVII No. 8. Published monthly by the Junior League of Brooklyn, Inc.
- Brooklyn Newsletter, 1978-1997 (Box 5)
  Borough President Howard Golden's Brooklyn newsletter.
- Brooklyn Review, 1963-1969 (Box 1)
  Published by the Better Brooklyn Committee.
- Brooklyn Sports Foundation newsletter, 1990 Summer (Box 1)
  Vol. 2 No. 1
- Brooklyn Union's New York, 1985 Fall (Box 5)
  A publication of the Brooklyn Union Gas Company.
  See also Gas Works, Sendout, and Starline.
- The Brooklyn Urban League Herald, 1975 Spring (Box 5)
  Vol. 1 No. 1. Published quarterly by the Brooklyn branch of the New York Urban League.
- Bulletin of the Brooklyn Library Council, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  Vol. 8 Nos. 2-3 and Vol. IX No. 2
- CAMBA Courier, 2010 Winter (Box 1)
  Vol. 4 No. 1. Published by CAMBA (Church Avenue Merchant Block Association), based in Flatbush.
- City Green, 1982-1998 (Box 2)
  Published by the Prospect Park Environmental Center (est. 1978), which became the Brooklyn Center for the Urban Environment (BCUE) in 1990.
  Brooklyn Center for the Urban Environment collection (BCMS.0066)
- Community News and Information, 1997 June (Box 2)
  Published by Community Board #9.
- Coney Isl-O-Phile, 1992-1998 (Box 2)
  Vol. 1 Nos. 1, 3, 7. Published by Coney Island, USA.
- Congregation Beth Elohim News Letter, 1992 October 27 (Box 2)
- Council Ring, 1937 June 26 (Box 2)
  Vol. XI No. 25. "The Voice of Brooklyn Scouts" (Boy Scouts).
- Did You Know That..., circa 2008-2009 (Box 2)
  Published by Terry Lawler, Prudential Douglas Elliman, Park Slope.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Some issues were the gift of Clark Marlor and some were the gift of Terry Lawler.
- Dodgers Alumni News, 1989 May-June (Box 2)
  Vol. 6 No. 1. Published by and primarily focuses on the Los Angeles Dodgers but with some information about the Brooklyn Dodgers.
- Downtown Brooklyn, 2007-2010 (Box 2)
  "A quarterly newsletter brought to you by the three Downtown Brooklyn Business Improvement Districts (BIDs) and the Downtown Brooklyn Partnership."
- Eastern States Historical Clearing House, 1971-1975 (Box 2)
  Nos. 21, 23, 24, 28, 29. Published by the Brooklyn Center at Long Island University.
  See also Long Island University News.
- East Midwood Jewish Center Bulletin, 1957-1958 (Box 2)
  Vols. XXIV-XXVI
- Environmental Viewpoint, November 1972 (Box 2)
  Published by Citizens for a Better New York.
- FAC News, 1986-1994 (Box 2)
  "A bilingual publication of the Fifth Avenue Committee." [Park Slope]
  See also The Fifth Avenue Press and InFACt.
- The Fifth Avenue Press, 1995-1998 (Box 5)
  Published by the Fifth Avenue Committee (Park Slope).
  See also FAC News and InFACt.
- The Flatbush Faithful, 1991-1997 (Box 2, Folder 1991-1995, Box 3, Folder 1995-1997)
  Vols. 1-7. Published and edited by Norman E. Kurland and seems to be related to the Brooklyn Dodgers Baseball Hall of Fame.
- Fulton Mall News, 1979-1985 (Box 3)
  Vols. 3-9. Published by the Fulton Mall Improvement Association, Inc.
- Gas Works, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
  Issues 1 and 2. Published by Brooklyn Union Gas.
  See also Brooklyn Union's New York, Sendout, and Starline.
- Gateway, 1984 Spring/Summer (Box 3)
  Published by United States Department of the Interior, National Park Service, Gateway National Recreation Area.
  See also Urban Outdoors Review.
- Gay Friends and Neighbors (G.F.N.), 1988 June (Box 3)
  Vol. 6 No. 6. Published by G.F.N. Gay Friends and Neighbors Ltd.
- The Good News Paper, 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  Vol. III Nos. 3 and 11. Published by Flare Corp., "the one stop print shop," Nostrand Avenue.
- Gowanus Arts Exchange, 1997 September/October (Box 3)
  Vol. 3 No. 1. "The Gowanus Arts Exchange is the home of Brooklyn's Center for Lesbian and Gay Arts and Artists, and of the Brooklyn Dance Consortium."
- Gravesend Historical Society newsletter, 1973-1975, 1977 (Box 3)
- The Green Machine, 1985 (Box 3)
  Vol. 1. Published by the Parks and Recreation Department/Brooklyn.
- Guy Pierrepont's Weekly Society Bulletin, 1941-1942, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Box 5, Folder 1941-1942 originals)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original issues from Volumes 1 and 2 are in very fragile condition and should not be used unless the provided preservation photocopies will not suffice for the researcher's purpose.
- InFACt, 2002 Summer (Box 3)
  Published by the Fifth Avenue Committee (FAC).
  See also FAC News and The Fifth Avenue Press.
- Inside Coney Island, 1986 Spring (Box 3)
  Published by the Coney Island Hysterical Society.
- Italian American Review, 1965-1977 (Box 3)
  Published by the Italian Historical Society, Brooklyn.
- Jubilee Times, 1994 September (Box 3)
  Published by the St. Charles Jubilee Senior Center in Brooklyn Heights.
- The Key / The Key Hole, 1970, 1975 (Box 3)
  Published by Central Brooklyn Model Cities.
- Kings County Grand Juror, 1960-1967 (Box 3)
  Vols. VII-XI. Published by the Kings County Grand Jurors' Association.
- L'Chaim, 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  Issues 41, 46, 50, 52-54, 56, 57. "The Weekly Publication for every Jewish Person." Published by Lubavitch Youth Organization.
- The Long Island Pioneer, 1962 Spring (Box 3)
  Published quarterly by the Long Island Empire Chapter, Telephone Pioneers of America, Brooklyn.
- Long Island University News, Brooklyn Center, Zeckendorf Campus, 1961 June (Box 3)
  Vol. 9 No. 5
- Luhn's Rugby Bulletin, 1912 April-May (Box 3)
  Vol. 1, No. 9. Published by G.J. Luhn, Rugby Investors Building Company.
- The Midwout Magazine, 1911-1917 (Box 3)
  Vols. 1-5. Published by Snyder of Flatbush.
- The Namm-ite, 1949-1952 (Box 3)
  Nos. 2-26. Published for Namm's employees.
  See also Nammson News.
- Nammson News, 1920 June (Box 3)
  Published by and for the employees of A.I. Namm and Son, Brooklyn.
  See also The Namm-ite.
- Neptune Service News, 1943-1945 (Box 3)
  Vols. 1-3. Published monthly by the Neptune Service League of Brighton Beach.
  Gift of Charles K. Stein, 2019 (CBH accession number 2022.039).
- News Digest, 1964, 1972-1973, 1980 (Box 4)
  Vols. 7-22. "Published monthly...for the information and guidance of the employees of the Brooklyn Post Office."
- News from Flatlands, 1984 (Box 4)
  Published jointly by the Flatlands Chamber of Commerce and the Flatlands Historical Foundation.
- New York City Housing Authority Management News Letter - Red Hook Houses, 1967 March-April (Box 4)
  Vol. XVIV No. 2
- The New York Navy Yard Shipworker, 1941-1966 (Box 4, Folder Hard copies, Reel 1, Reel 1941-1946, Reel 2, Reel 1947-1953, Reel 3, Reel 1954-1959, Reel 4, Reel 1960-1966)
  "Official publication of the New York Navy Yard, Brooklyn, New York [Brooklyn Navy Yard]. Distributed free to all Yard employees."
  Hard copy issues Vol. III No. 33 (1944) and Vol. IV No. 17 (1945)
  Microfilm 1941-1966
- Nordic News (Nordisk Tidende), 2002-2005, 2010 (Box 4)
  The quarterly newsletter of the Scandinavian East Coast Museum.
  Another publication with the same title is available on microfilm. See the Local newspapers on microfilm collection (BCMS.0028).
- Nuggets, 1930-1949 (Box 4)
  Issues from Vols. 7-43. Published by George W. Pease and Son, Inc., funeral directors, Nostrand Avenue.
- The Old Stone House Gazette, 2006 Winter/Spring (Box 4)
  "A newsletter for members and friends of the Old Stone House."
- The Paragon Progressive, 1966-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1966-1970, Box 5, Folder 1971)
  Vol. 1 Nos. 1-2, Vol. 2 No. 3. Published by the Paragon Progressive Federal Credit Union and Paragon Progressive Community Association, Inc.
- Positive Focus, 2003 (Box 4)
  Nos. 15-17. Published by Positive Focus, Inc., a nonprofit center for emerging photoartists.
  The collection Real Brooklyn, a day in our lives photographs (2007.041) documents a 2003 Positive Focus exhibition.
- Prospect Park, 1983-1989 (Box 5)
  Seasonal guides published by the Park with grant assistance and later by the Prospect Park Alliance after its founding in April 1987.
  See also V.I.P.P. Newsletter.
- The Red Legged Devil, 1985 (Box 4)
  Vol. 6 No. 2. The newsletter of the Society for the Historical Preservation of the Brooklyn State Militia Infantry.
  See also 14th Brooklyn Society News.
- Republican Report, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  Vols. 14-15. Published by the Douglas MacArthur Republican Club, Brooklyn.
- Sendout, 1991-1998 (Box 5)
  Employee publication at Brooklyn Union (formerly Brooklyn Union Gas).
  See also Brooklyn Union's New York, Gas Works, Starline.
- SIAC News, 1998 July (Box 4)
  Vol. XVI No. 6. A publication for employees of Securities Industry Automation Corporation, MetroTech Center, Brooklyn.
- So This Is Flatbush, 1986 Summer (Box 4)
  Vol. 9 No. 3. Published by the Flatbush Development Corporation.
- The Spirit of Augustana, 1985 Fall (Box 4)
  Published by Augustana Lutheran Home, Bensonhurst.
- The Spirit of Flatbush, 1975, 1992 (Box 4)
  Vol. 2 No. 6 and Vol. 5 No. 4. Published quarterly by the Flatbush Historical Society and Town of Flatbush (Civic and) Cultural Association, Inc.
- The Staff, 1935-1936 (Box 4)
  Vols. 1-2. "A paper to be published regularly by Brooklyn College Staff. It is a political paper, exressing the program of the Communist Party, with especial reference to the problems of teachers and students in Brooklyn College."
  The first issue's masthead reads "Brooklyn College Staff" and Vol. 2 No. 3 reads "Student and Staff." All other issues in the collection are titled "The Staff."
- Starline, 1991 Fall (Box 4)
  Published by Brooklyn Union Gas.
  See also Brooklyn Union's New York, Sendout, and Gas Works.
- The Third Rail, 1975 January-March (Box 4)
  Vol. 1 No. 3. This publication is not Brooklyn-specific but the bulk of this issue is devoted to reprinting a 1906 article from the official publication of the Brooklyn Rapid Transit Employees' Benefit Association.
- Tzivos HaShem Children's Newsletter, 1989 Summer (Box 4)
  Vol. 8 No. 5. Published by Machne Israel, Inc. Tzvios HaShem.
- Urban Outdoors Review, 1997 Summer/Fall (Box 4)
  Published by Neighborhood Open Space Coalition/Friends of Gateway.
  See also Gateway.
- V.I.P.P. Newsletter, 1986-1988 (Box 4)
  Published for Volunteers in Prospect Park.
  See also Prospect Park.
- Wash Ave, 2012 Spring (Box 4)
  A publication of the Washington Avenue-Prospect Heights Association.
- Ye Long Islande Almanack, 1930-1931 (Box 4)
  Vol. 1 Nos. 1-6. Published by the Home Title Insurance Company.
- Youth on the Rise, 1993 January (Box 4)
  "The Newspaper of Project Reach Youth"'s journalism program Project Express. "Written and developed by teens from Park Slope and Sunset Park."
- The "Y" Gazette, 1943 June (Box 4)
  Published by Community Y.M. and Y.W.H.A. (Young Men's and Young Women's Hebrew Association), Brownsville.
- YWCA News, Activities, and Class Schedules, 1994-1995, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 1994-1995, Box 5, Folder 1997)
  See also Brooklyn YWCA Wire.
- YWCA Wire, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
  Vols. 3-4
  See also YWCA News, Activities, and Class Schedules.